CHRIS RUGG

47 Harrison Avenue, Red Bank NJ 07701- christophersrugg@gmail.com - 404-538-7247

Skills Summary

Experienced Product Owner with a demonstrated history of success in the digital experience space. Strong Agile, Negotiation, Solution Selling, Omnichannel, Enterprise Software Integration, Adobe Marketing & Analytics Cloud and Partnership skills. Ability to cross between marketing and Technical disciplines.

Education

Degree / Date of Graduation

BA Business Administration / Concentration Marketing – Strayer University 2016

Experience

AT&T

Senior Technical Product Manager - att.com - Adobe Marketing & Analytics Clouds - https://www.business.att.com/learn.html , AT&T Brand Center May 2013 – Mar 2018

I was responsible for the UX delivery and Product Management of att.com, att.com/learn and the Brand Center. This included defining the core product vision, goals, functionality, requirements, creating three agile scrum teams, training, analytics, process, product road maps, product documentation, feature backlogs, product user stories, use cases, user flows, logic flows, functional specifications, prioritizing development activities and managing the delivery of all three products.

I interfaced with UX design, Branding, Executive Management, Internal Stakeholders, Development, Environment Management and the PMO. I managed the initial implementation and three subsequent upgrades of the Adobe Marketing Cloud. I also managed the back-end development team for six months after the development lead left the group. I transitioned the lead development position to one of my direct reports after helping my direct report get promoted to Senior Technical Director. All three of these products were static sites when I started. I managed the movement of all pages to the Adobe Marketing & Analytics clouds

and the complete responsive redesign of all three products. The time of content delivery was reduced from days to minutes. Content can be personalized, and Analytics are now available to marketing.

AT&T

Associate Technical Director - Omnichannel Strategy April 2012 – April 2013

Responsible for omnichannel strategy and road map for the Consumer Digital Experience Sales team. Product Development Manager for store level inventory and buy online pick up in store projects. Documented existing standalone processes and created a plan for how these processes could be brought together under an omnichannel architecture. Managed these products from initial concept through three months post deployment.

AT&T

Sr. Technical Director – Product Management - Online eCommerce & Marketing - att.com

Sep 2009 - April 2012

Responsible for strategy, roadmaps, setting up two agile scrum teams, business requirements, product backlog management, marketing and delivery for all AT&T att.com online eCommerce, marketing web sites and mobile applications. During my tenure I was responsible for upgrading the existing commerce site from a static web interface to Adobe AEM, 5. I also managed the redesign of the user experience from static to a responsive and optimizing the sites to meet the massive site volume increase during new iPhone launches.

AT&T

Sr. Technical Director – Product Management - Account Management & Online Care at AT&T Mobility

Oct 2003 – Sep 2009

I was responsible for the business strategy, product development, product management, setting up six agile scrum teams, product road map and business requirements for the

MyCingular / MyAtt Web site and iPhone application from concept to fully operational. This involved bringing separate account management systems together into one instance. These two account management systems contained close to three thousand bugs. I was able to successfully bring the two systems together and reduce the bug count to eleven when I moved to the online commerce product. I also brought an iPhone account management prototype to my management for funding with a business case to build out the application. My management agreed to fund the development and I managed the product development. In less than six months this iPhone application doubled the amount of digital payments, greatly increased paperless billing. Add- on feature sales at the end of the year equaled the total number of features sold in all retail channels combined.

Awards and Acknowledgements

AT&T Interactive Marketing Employee of the Quarter

I was acknowledged as the employee of the quarter by my management 1st quarter 2012

Junior Achievement Contributor 2008 - 2018